I think post COVID we're much more
conspiratorial than we were pre because
all of our conspiracies came true
during the COVID era. So, it made it
made everybody like, "Mhm, I trust
nothing and no one."
But,
you know, for example, I know there are
a lot of people questioning whether the
CIA had some control over the Butler
shooter of President Trump.
>> Right. There's been a question about
whether they had any knowledge
whatsoever about what happened to
Charlie Kirk.
Um, do you think that the CIA possibly
has any role in in cases like that?
I don't know, but I can tell you it's
absolutely possible. You know, when when
Joe Kent, whether you like Joe Kent's
politics or not,
you cannot doubt the man's patriotism.
He's walked the walk.
And if he says that he was forbidden
from having his analysts follow
investigative leads,
you have to ask why.
Why Why do we not know more about the
Butler shooter
and the circumstances surrounding the
Butler shooting? I grew up 15 miles from
Butler. We never missed a county fair
and farm show. I've been there a
thousand times.
Um, that should have been easy to
investigate.
Right? They're all patriotic people.
It's a red county and in a red part of
the state and
and then the President of the United
States takes a shot to the ear.
So, why
why were comprehensive, full, complete
investigations not carried out? Why was
Joe Kent told that he could not pursue
investigative leads in the Charlie Kirk
case? And one other thing about the
Charlie Kirk case that I've always been
confused about, why is the FBI involved
at all?
The The crime took place in Utah.
The shooter is from Utah. He set out
that day from Utah. He went to a
location in Utah.
This is a state police case for for this
the Utah state police. Why in the world
is the FBI calling the shots? Unless
they know something that we don't know.
Unless they know something something
that they haven't revealed that
indicates
you know, either
cross
interstate
some investigative lead that came across
state lines or some kind of
international involvement. But my god,
transparency is everything. And like you
said, Megan, in the post-COVID area era
where where
we've learned definitively that we can't
trust what the government is telling us,
then wouldn't transparency make that all
go away?
Well, as I understand it, as I I haven't
really been conspiratorial in my adult
life at all in any part of my life.
But I do I do want to understand the
theories because some of them do turn
out to be right over time.
And as I understand it, the theory kind
of revolves around MK Ultra.
Like either, you know, they unleash an
operation on a vulnerable target to try
to get that target possibly the shooter
in Butler to do what they want him to
do. But can you walk me through what you
know about MK Ultra? Sure. MK Ultra was
a was a CIA operation that was
that was conceived in 1952. It began to
be implemented in 1953 and really took
hold in 1955. It did a lot of different
things.
It There were even sub operations within
MK Ultra, MK Chickwit, MK Midnight
something or other. Lots of them. The
bottom line was this.
There was a source that the CIA
recruited, a Chinese communist source,
who said that the Chinese government was
experimenting with mind control. That's
where the the idea of the Manchurian
Candidate came out, which led to a
popular movie in the late 19 1950s
starring Frank Sinatra.
In fact, the Chinese were not
experimenting on mind control. The
Russians were.
And the source was wrong. But the CIA
believed that it was behind the eight
ball and if the Chinese were
experimenting in mind control, then we
needed by God to experiment in mind
control and to figure out if we could
sort of create a Chinese zombie
who could then work his way through the
the upper echelons of the Chinese
Communist Party and take over China and
then do away with communism and we all
live happily ever after. That's how it
started.
So, the CIA went about doing this in all
of the worst possible ways.
Right around the time that MK Ultra was
was being hatched,
a scientist in Switzerland
invented something called LSD.
And LSD did these incredible things and
it could manipulate your mind. You could
see colors that didn't exist. You could
see people that didn't exist and maybe
if we microdosed people with this new
LSD, then maybe we could control their
minds. The CIA began by using it on
their own people.
Now, we know that one of those CIA
contractors actually jumped out of a
hotel window and committed suicide
because he thought he could fly. That's
been well documented.
Then they decided, you know, maybe
experimenting on our own people
isn't the best way to go about this.
Maybe we should just experiment on
random citizens in San Francisco.
And so they went to San Francisco, they
rented a safe house, they recruited a
bunch of prostitutes and sent the
prostitutes out on the street to pick up
dates.
Bring the dates back to the safe house,
dose them with LSD without their
knowledge, and then try to get them to
reveal their innermost secrets
just to see if the CIA could collect
those.
Another part of MKUltra, also in San
Francisco,
was they decided to
to create um a virus or a bacterium, in
this case it was a bacterium, that they
could just
push out into the air and see how many
people they could infect. They waited
until an unusually foggy day where the
air is very heavy and sitting close to
the ground.
And all around the city of San
Francisco, as well as on the public
transit system, they released this
bacterium.
And eight people came down with this
very rare upper respiratory infection.
So then they tried to couple that and
the release of the bacterium with the
LSD. Can we release LSD into the air?
They experimented in a small village in
France by dosing the yeast in the
village's only bakery with LSD.
Everybody in the in the village ate
bread from that bakery and everybody
went nuts for a day or two.
And so that was another, you know,
successful operation.
In the end,
um
nobody's mind was taken over. We didn't
bring down Chinese communism or Russian
communism or anything else. It was a
failure.
But then Congress got wind of it. The
Church Committee got wind of it in 1975
and called the Director of Central
Intelligence to testify. And then at the
testimony, specifically ordered him to
not destroy the documents.
He immediately went back to CIA
headquarters and told everybody,
"Destroy everything."
That's why what we have today is only
15% of the MK Ultra documents.
Everything else was destroyed in 1975.
Now, he was held in contempt of
Congress, and by God, he was fined $150.
And um Right.
>> Yeah, and all the uh CIA employees
chipped in to pay the $150 fine for him.
Yeah. And and a negative presumption was
against him that he had something to
hide.
>> right. But I think as a result of that,
it's part of the reason why people now
suspect government involvement in
everything.
>> is. You know, the the things that we
don't feel like we're getting full
transparency on, it's it's a CIA
conspiracy, or maybe an NSA conspiracy,
or maybe an FBI conspiracy. Yes.
>> it's undermining
what
what probably are CIA and FBI
conspiracies. Do you know what I mean?
Like not everything is a conspiracy by
the government, but for sure they are
doing some things that we should know
about. So, how do you tell the
difference? I think you're exactly
right. And the only way to tell the
difference
is through robust congressional
oversight. Something that we have not
had since the early 1980s. We're
screwed.
>> Because what what are they? They're
cheerleaders for the CIA and the FBI on
the intelligence committees and on the
judiciary committees. They're
cheerleaders. You know, when I got home
from prison, I was invited to uh a
dinner at the Greek ambassador's
residence. And I went there. And um
there was a a Democratic senator there
who happens to be a member of the
intelligence committee. And I went up to
him. He came up to me, actually. And he
said, "Hey, welcome home. We were really
pulling for you."
And I said, "Uh thanks, Senator. But I
got to tell you, I I expected more from
you. I thought you would have been more
helpful to me."
And he got angry. And he said, "Look, it
took everything I had just to not lose
my security clearance."
And I said, "Oh, you're afraid of them.
You're not overseeing them. You're
afraid of them."
And he walked away from me, but I was
right. He was afraid of them. They're
all afraid.
And so they just tow the line.
Remember who was it that said uh about
Trump like, "You mess with the
three-letter agency. You mess with CIA
and they will make you pay
>> uh for the rest of your life." I can't
remember
>> Schumer. He said they have nine ways
from Sunday to make your life miserable.
To make you pay. But here's my question
cuz I heard you on um Diary of a CEO
saying the CIA can they can they can
wrest control of your car. You know, our
cars have these big brains now that I
mean,
you know, if the car company can and
like whatever the the service is if you
get into an accident, you can just sort
of say, "Help me." If they can get in
there, sure, I bet it's hackable by
somebody else to the point where they
could potentially drive your car right
off the road.
>> Yes. If they could do that, then why
would they ever have to
do anything more explicit? Why would
they ever have to do mind control over
anybody at a at a rally in Pennsylvania
if that's what they want. You know, like
there are there would be ways of getting
rid of you that would be so undetectable
and and not suspicious that they could
be doing that all the time. They
wouldn't have to go about mind control,
MK Ultra, LSD. You know what I'm saying?
So that to me that's that undermines the
theory that they're doing any of these
public executions explicitly or behind
the scenes. I I think that's right, but
think of it this way, too. I'm going to
tell you a little funny little anecdote
about one of my promotion panels. I had
been working with a psychologist in the
CIA's Counterterrorism Center to come up
with out of outside the box ideas on how
to recruit spies to steal secrets. And
she happened to also sit on my promotion
panel.
And she said in my promotion panel in in
great support of my promotion. She said,
"John Kiriakou will come up with 40
different ideas for an operation. 36 of
them are insane, but four of them are
going to be really good."
So, imagine sitting around the table and
somebody comes up with an idea to put an
explosive in Fidel Castro's cigar. Well,
that's a stupid idea.
If you're going to get close enough to
put an explosive in the
cigar,
just shoot him in the head, for example,
if that's what you really want to do.
So, there are a lot of people sitting
around a lot of conference room tables
at the CIA coming up with really stupid
ideas.
And then there are nodding heads all the
all around the table saying, "Yeah,
that's a great idea. We should do that."
So, you know, the bottom line is this.
We know thanks to WikiLeaks and the
Vault 7 revelations that the CIA can
remotely take over your car. They can
make you drive off a bridge or into a
tree or into an abutment and and kill
you if they want to. They can turn your
smart TV into a microphone. They can
reverse engineer your speaker to turn
into a microphone so they can listen to
everything you're saying even when the
TV is off.
The The technology is 20 years ahead of
what anybody else thinks the technology
is.
I mean, I don't want to be a Pollyanna
about it, but they're they're not
supposed to do that without a warrant.
Are they doing that without a
warrant?
>> Without a warrant.
You know, at the CIA
>> I mean, that's disturbing.
>> God, in training they they used to tell
us all the time, "Our job is to break
the law." And I remember saying,
"Yeah, but not here."
The job is to break the law over there.
You know, I was perfectly happy and and
on multiple occasions actively
participated in, you know, breaking into
people's houses or offices and planting
bugs and cameras. We're the good guys.
That's what we have to do. This is to
protect the United States. But not here.
You need a warrant. And besides, the CIA
is forbidden by law from doing anything
operationally inside the United States.
That's what the FBI is for. I just never
understood this. Like, why isn't it that
clear to everybody? I don't know.
Do you think the FBI is doing similar
behaviors or is this all CIA? You know,
it was my experience when I was working
with the FBI, and I worked with the FBI
for years and years, that they they
really were sticklers for the law, where
the CIA wasn't.
Um I remember even saying one time, I'm
going to I'm going to fudge the details
here for obvious reasons, but
they we were talking, a couple of us CIA
people were talking to a group from the
FBI, and they were saying what
difficulty they were having infiltrating
a domestic terrorist group. And I said,
"Oh, no, I I I got you covered." I said,
"There was this group that that we took
care of. We we just didn't have access
to them. So, what we did is we found one
of them." It was only like six members
of this terrorist group. We found one,
and we said, "Hey, listen, Muhammad,
your friend Abdallah I'm from the CIA,
and Abdallah told me that that you're
you'd be a good guy for me to talk to
cuz Abdallah works for me, and and he
said you'd like to work for me, too."
Well, the guy runs screaming from the
room, but he goes back, and he kills
Abdallah.
And then we And then we tell Rashid,
"Hey, listen, we were talking about
about Abdallah with Muhammad. You know,
Muhammad's one of our guys, and and he
told us that Abdallah was a bad guy."
And then Rashid kills Muhammad.
And then by the end of the year,
this terrorist group doesn't exist
anymore. And the FBI guy said, "Oh my
god, that's so illegal. We couldn't
possibly do that." And I was like, "Oh,
it never even occurred to me that that
might be illegal."
Thanks for watching this clip. If you're
new here, subscribe. We got a whole lot
more goodness where that came from.
Would love to hear your feedback. You
can email me, too. Megan, m e g y n at
megynkelly.com or just leave a comment
below. But, join the community by
becoming a subscriber. We really, really
value your input and your support. We
may not always agree, but we are always
going to talk about it and respect. No
BS, no agenda, no fear. Think about
this. In 2006, $20,000 equaled roughly
33 oz of gold at spot price. At today's
prices, those 33 oz would be worth about
$165,000.
That's why many smart Americans
diversify a portion of their savings
into precious metals. And that's why you
should consider buying gold from Birch
Gold Group. For thousands of years, gold
has been a store of wealth. And today,
it's a crucial part of any balanced
strategy. Even better, Birch Gold can
help you convert an existing IRA or 401k
into a tax-sheltered retirement account
in gold. Just text MK to the number
989898 to receive your free info kit on
gold. There's no obligation, just useful
information. With an A+ rating with the
Better Business Bureau and tens of
thousands of happy customers, let Birch
Gold help you diversify with gold. Now,
that's peace of mind. Again, text MK to
today.